Ladies
Speaker 1: and gentlemen please welcome to the stage author and radio host Larry Elder.
Thank
Speaker 2: you. Oh my goodness. I can feel the love.
Nobody took
Speaker 2: a knee. Thank
you all for coming
Speaker 3: out. I can just feel all the energy, all the enthusiasm. They told me I have no more than 20 minutes to speak, so I'll
Speaker 4: speak quickly.
I get
Speaker 4: paid by the word. So I'm from L.A. I arrive in the Charlotte airport to come here to Greenville. And
when I'm in
Speaker 4: Charlotte, black guy in the airport walks down. He's got a T-shirt on that says, I can't be calm. I have a black child.
That's exactly what I
Speaker 4: said. I said, what? I
can't be calm
Speaker 4: anymore.
Speaker 4: I have a black child. Obviously, what he's referring to is this narrative that the police are out mowing down black people just because they're black.
It's fascinating
Speaker 4: to me.
I am a big
Speaker 4: sports fan, and one of my favorite sports teams of all time is the so-called Fab Five.
You might
Speaker 4: remember them. They were five freshmen. They started Michigan.
They made
Speaker 4: back-to-back Final Fours.
One
Speaker 4: of the Fab Five is a guy named Jalen Rose. Jalen Rose had a long career, 13 years or so in the NBA, good career, became a sportscaster, and he's woke. He's one of these guys that believes in this narrative. Now, I once heard somebody tell Jalen Rose
that they felt he had
Speaker 4: a mediocre career, that he came out of University of Michigan, a lot of fanfare, 13-year career is a long time in the NBA, the average career is three
years,
but
Speaker 4: he did not achieve the same numbers that some people thought he should achieve. And he said, very calmly, "You see, that's the kind of comment that would be made by
Speaker 3: somebody who's never played basketball at the highest level. Because if you knew this, I played for three teams," he said. "I played for Denver, and when I was in Denver, who set the record for assists for a rookie in Denver?" Then I got traded to Indiana. I had a different position. Top ten, my position. Then I got traded to Chicago.
Speaker 3: Who, in the year I was at Chicago, in the top ten with 20 points, six dimes,
Speaker 5: five boards? Me. "Holly at your boy!" He said. And my point is, he very carefully, skillfully, logically, with facts, with data, outlined what he thought was a very successful career. And
he's right. The
Speaker 5: same mind, when it comes to this, "Oh, why does this keep happening?"
Speaker 5: Oh, why are they doing this? Oh, Doc Rivers, the coach of the LA Clippers. Why do these things keep happening? Why do we love America? America doesn't love us
back. I
Speaker 5: saw Doc Rivers speak at our country club in LA once. Logical, structured, facts, data, when it comes to his profession. If you apply the same mentality to this issue, you say to yourself,
well,
Speaker 5: million police-civilian interactions every year. Out
of those
Speaker 5: 50 million police interactions every year, there are 11 million arrests. Out
of those 11
Speaker 5: million arrests, 60,000 officers are assaulted.
After the
Speaker 5: 50 million interactions, 11 million arrests, 60,000 assaults, 1,000 people out of a population of 350 million people are killed every year by the police. Of that 1,000, almost all of them We're resisting with a weapon or resisting
violence.
Speaker 5: When you get down to the handful of white cops who killed an unarmed black person, and by the way, unarmed does not
Speaker 3: mean not dangerous. Michael Brown was unarmed. His DNA was found on the officer's gun. So if you are looking at the percentage of white cops who killed unarmed black men who are not reasonably perceived as a threat, you're talking about less than 4% of all the people the police shoot every year.
Speaker 3: 500 of them are white, 250 of them are black,
the
Speaker 5: police kill at least as many unarmed whites as they do unarmed blacks. Name one!
'Cause nobody cares. Van
Speaker 5: Jones doesn't care, CNN doesn't care, MSNB Hee Haw doesn't care. They only care when it's a white cop killing a black person.
Now, if these
Speaker 5: guys spent
Speaker 5: a fraction of the time, analyzing this issue the way they analyze their own careers, they would realize the narrative is B.S. Now, just having a B.S. narrative, and neither here nor there, if it doesn't have any downsides, this has huge downsides. First side, the cop side. You're a cop, why in the world would you be proactive? Why in the world would you try and stop crime? Why in the world would you do anything other than answer 911 squad cars? Why?
Speaker 5: what's the upside you're going to be accused of engaging in police brutality institutional racism so screw it cops pull back they become more passive it's known as the ferguson effect
and what
Speaker 5: happens crime goes up and who's hurt the very black and brown people that the so-called black
Speaker 3: lives matter proponents and their
sympathizers claim they care about
What's the other thing
Speaker 5: that happens? If you're a young black man and you've been told all your life, "They are out to get me." Jesse Jackson's told me that. Farrakhan's told me that. Sharpton's told me that. Van Jones has told me that. Don Lamont's told me that. Well, if I get pulled over, why wouldn't I be wary? Why wouldn't I think this guy's going to do something to me? Why wouldn't I be ready to have a confrontation? So you have affected both sides with this lie.
Speaker 5: it is a lie.
Speaker 3: The youngest tenured professor in the history of Harvard is a black guy named Roland Fryer. He just knew that the police were using deadly force against blacks just because they were black, and was kind of surprised that no one had ever done a comprehensive study about it.
So he
Speaker 3: decided he would do it. He knew it was going to confirm
it. And
He
Speaker 3: looked at his results, and looked at his results, and looked at his results, and he said, "This is the most surprising finding of my career." Not only did he find the cops were not shooting blacks just because they were black,
Speaker 5: he found out the cops were more hesitant, more reluctant to pull the trigger on a black suspect than on a white
suspect.
It's a
Speaker 5: lie. It is not true. In the last 50, 60 years, according to the CDC,
Speaker 3: the rate at which blacks have been shot by the police has declined 75%. Meanwhile, 15,000 homicides every year in this country. Half of them are black victims, and they ain't being shot by Confederate generals. They're not
being killed.
by the
Speaker 3: Aryan brothers. They're not being killed by the KKK, they're being killed by other black people in the neighborhood.
Speaker 5: Chicago, Labor Day Lincoln, what are we talking about? 50 people killed, shot, five killed. The weekend before that, 66 people shot, five killed. The weekend before that, 55 people shot, 10 killed. Where's Black Lives Matter? Where are these people?
Black kid kills
Speaker 5: another black kid, just a dead fly.
White
Speaker 5: cop kills
Speaker 3: a black kid, international news. You're being manipulated, you're being used, you're being played.
And the
Speaker 3: media does it for one reason and one reason only, ratings and clicks. The Democrats do it because they
want black
Speaker 3: people to vote for them. And they want white sympathizers to vote for them.
And the idea
Speaker 3: is to get 95% of black people voting for the Democratic Party. Think
about that.
Why
Speaker 3: would 95 percent of black people vote for the Democratic Party if it weren't for the perception that America is racist and we Democrats wear the white hat in that fight, and those guys over there, they wear the black hat? That's their theme. Because if you take away that, let's look at abortion. 25 percent of the abortions are on black women. Black people are more anti-abortion than whites are. Look
at the stats.
Speaker 3: Same-sex marriage. Black people are more opposed to same-sex marriage than whites, however you feel about it. You're talking about education? I went to a high school called Crenshaw High School. If you saw the movie Boys in the Hood, that was
my high
Speaker 3: school. Ice-T went to my high
Speaker 4: school 10 years after I did and chose it because it's a crip
Speaker 3: school, meaning the gang crips control it.
And
Speaker 3: in a recent article in the LA Times, 3% of kids from my former high school can do math at grade level. Now, what parent within a geographical area of that school sends his or her kid who just graduated from middle school to a school where only 3% can do math and it's a crip school?
Speaker 3: The Democrats are mandating that your child go there whether you like it or not. Republicans want to give you an option out of an underperforming government school, and they're
the bad guys.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): Baltimore, where
Speaker 3: Freddie Gray died. The time he died, he died in police custody. The mayor is black. The police department
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): chief is black.
The
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): number two guy in the police department is black. The state attorney who brought the charges against six officers, black. Three of the six officers, black. The judge before whom two of the
Speaker 5: cases were tried, black. City council, all Democrat, mostly black. At the time, the U.S. Attorney General was black, Loretta Lynch, and the U.S. President was black, Barack Obama. And we're talking about institutional racism when black people are running the institution? Are you
kidding me?
Speaker 5: What did comedian Wanda Sykes say after Obama got elected? How are you going to complain about the man when you
are the
Speaker 5: man? Knock it off. You're getting people killed. Meanwhile, 13 high schools in Baltimore where zero percent are math
Speaker 3: proficient and another half a dozen where one percent is. That's
half
The
Speaker 3: high schools in Baltimore were either 0% or math proficient, or 1% is, and we're talking about police brutality? Are
Speaker 4: you kidding me? You're being
manipulated. I
Speaker 4: don't know anybody who had a harder hand dealt than my father. My father was born in Athens, Georgia. His irresponsible
Speaker 3: mother threw him out of the house when he was 13 years old because he was quarreling with his mother's then boyfriend.
My
Speaker 3: father leaves, picks up anything he can do. Ultimately, he became a Pullman
Speaker 4: porter on the trains. In those days, they were the largest private employer of blacks in those days. And my dad came
Speaker 3: out to California once, and it was sunny, and you could walk into a restaurant
and sit
Speaker 3: down and be served?
Speaker 4: He couldn't believe it. So he'd made a mental note that maybe someday he'd relocate to California. Pearl Harbor, my dad joined the Marines.
Speaker 4: Right. Semper Fi, bro. And I said, "Dad, why?" And my dad said, "Two reasons." You know what they are. They go where the action is, and I love
Speaker 3: those uniforms.
My dad is
Speaker 3: stationed on the island of Guam. Bombs fall, war is over, goes back to Chattanooga where he met and married
my mom.
Speaker 3: My dad was in charge of cooking
Speaker 4: facilities in the military. He was a staff sergeant. My dad can look at a cake and tell you what's in it. That's how good he
is.
He
Speaker 4: wants a job as a short order cook, 1945. He goes to restaurant after restaurant after restaurant in Chattanooga, where he had met and married
my mom, and
Speaker 4: they said, "We don't hire niggers."
My dad
Speaker 4: goes to an unemployment office. The lady says, "You went through the wrong door." My dad goes out to the hall, sees colored only, goes to that door to the same lady who sent him
out.
My dad
Speaker 4: went home to my mom and said, "This is BS. I'm going to California. I'm going to get me a job as a short-order cook. I'll send for you after I get a job." My dad comes out to LA, where I live now, walks around, restaurant to restaurant to restaurant. "I'm sorry. We only hire people with references."
Speaker 4: said, "I need a reference
to make eggs?" He
Speaker 4: even offered to work for free for two weeks.
Speaker 4: then write me a reference. Nobody would do that. He was treated the same way in LA as he was in Chattanooga. They were just a little more polite about it. He went to an unemployment office, only one door, and
he sat
Speaker 4: there, and the lady finally calls him up after a day and a half and says, "I have something. I don't know whether or not you want it." My dad said, "Of course I'm going to want it. It's
a job
Speaker 4: at Nabisco Brand Bread cleaning toilets." My dad did that for 10 years.
Speaker 4: He worked for another bread company at the same time, full-time job cleaning toilets for that bread company as well. He went to night school
Speaker 3: two or three nights a week to get his GED because he got kicked out of the house and he never went back to school at the eighth grade.
And he
Speaker 3: cooked for a family on the
Speaker 4: weekend. The man never slept, which is why he was so grouchy all the time and why I had such a difficult relationship with him. And my dad told my brothers and me the following, "Hard
Speaker 7: work
Speaker 8: wins."
Speaker 7: You
get out of life what
Speaker 3: you put into it. And he said, Larry, you are not in control of the outcome, but you are 100% in control of the effort. And before you moan and whine about what somebody did to you or said to you, go to the nearest mirror, look at it and say, what could I
Speaker 4: have done to change the outcome?
Speaker 4: And finally he said, no matter how hard you work, no matter how good you are, bad crap will happen. How you address that bad crap will tell your mother and me if we raised a man.
By the way, I wrote a book about
Speaker 4: all of this. It's called Dear Father, Dear Son, Two Lives, Eight Hours. About the eight hour conversation my dad and I had because I hated his guts when I was growing up. I didn't realize his background. I mean, I knew he didn't have
Speaker 4: relatives, because we never got any gifts from him, but I had no idea what his life was like. And he sat down and told me about everything he'd gone through. And at the end of this eight-hour conversation, this man was bigger and bigger and bigger, and Larry was smaller and smaller and smaller. And my dad was a lifelong Republican, and he always said this: "Democrats want to give you something for nothing. And when you try and get something for nothing, you almost always end
Speaker 3: up getting
Speaker 3: Nothing for something.
God bless you all. God bless our
Speaker 5: great country. We're going to win in November
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): 3rd.
He's going to triple
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): the black vote.
And we're going to win. God bless
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): you.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): Peace out.